NZ Citizen 021 022 58062 thiffanyjun@hotmail.com

> <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Portfolio</u> GitHub

# **Tiffany Wang**

### About me

Kia ora, I'm Tiff! I'm a **full-stack software developer** with an education and digital design background. I bring a huge amount of skills from my 7-year teaching experience, particularly my ability to emphasise, communicate, plan, and work in a team. My experience in web design also adds an extra layer of creativity to my software development work.

I fell in love with coding when I encountered HTML and CSS during a Web Design course. I heard from tech friends that Javascript is much harder which may deter me. It seems not true as after following a couple of Javascript tutorial videos, I can't wait to learn even more! Being able to learn new things every day, engage in constant problem-solving, and know that I can build remarkable software to solve real-world problems truly motivates me.

I'm currently working on building my <u>tech portfolio</u> and learning the AWS Cloud Practitioner Course.

When I'm not working, I enjoy cooking, hitting the gym, practicing hip-hop dance, and pampering my cat with tummy rubs.

## **Experience**

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

## Full-stack Software Developer

Dev Academy Aotearoa · Apprenticeship

- This was a 15-week, 800-hour full immersion software development bootcamp that mimics the real-world Agile development team with multiple projects that focus on both web development and people skills.
- Tech stack includes HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Knex, SQLite3, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs, and GitHub.
- In my final project, <u>Tiff's Donuts</u>, I acted as the Product Owner with five other team members where we developed a web application for users to create 3D donuts. The website includes rendering 3D models, interactions and scrolling effects using threeJS and React. During this intensive 7-day project, I had the opportunity to take the lead in introducing and implementing **React Three**Fiber, a technology not covered in our bootcamp. This experience was truly valuable as it showcased our team's dedication to collaborative problem-solving and our ability to adapt and learn on the fly.

Aug 2022- Jun 2023

## Freelance Web Designer

Freelance

- Provided logo design and UI/UX design for several volunteer-driven side projects including web interface design and Webflow building. Feel free to check my <u>design wonderland</u>.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Adobe Creative Suites, prototyping and design thinking skills.

#### Nov 2021- Jun 2023

#### Centre Administrator

Tots on Triton Childcare

- Demonstrated excellent customer service and communication skills.
- Streamlined administrative workflow, resulting in a 30% reduction in task time and significant productivity and cost savings.
- Served as the go-to tech support for teachers encountering issues with their computers and printers.
- Maintained well-organised records and documents that helped the service pass the Education Office Review.

Nov 2019- Nov 2021

## Career Break and Parental Leave

Multiple Ventures

• I had my pregnancy and parental leave while exploring the possibilities of career change including studying and completing a Graduate Diploma of Professional Accounting and Foundation Level Certified Tester from ASTQB.

Apr 2017- Nov 2019

#### Head Teacher

New Shoots Childcare Centre

- Took on a leadership role in guiding the team to deliver high-quality education and care for children.
- Facilitated collaborative discussions to develop tailored strategies that successfully transformed the classroom into the most calm and organised one.
- Designed an intuitive program planning board that effectively improved the consistency of centre program planning.
- Fostered distributed leadership and encouraged every team member to contribute their expertise to delivering quality services as a team.

Feb 2013- Apr 2017

## Registered Teacher

**Evolve Education Group** 

- Engaged in close collaboration with my team of educators to ensure the best outcomes for children.
- Consistently recognised by colleagues and parents for my ability to identify children's needs, demonstrating strong observational and empathy skills.
- Actively participated in reflective teaching sessions, fostering a culture of continuous improvement and learning.

#### Education

Web Development Training Scheme | Level 6

Dev Academy Aotearoa | 2023

Diploma in Digital Design (Web and Graphic Design)

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation | 2022 - 2023

Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting (Average A)

Auckland University of Technology | 2021-2022

Bachelor of Teaching

New Zealand Tertiary College | 2012 - 2014

## References

Available on request